<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alper Kilci&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alper Kilci&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:48:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things to write about</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-07-02-things-to-write-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-07-02-things-to-write-about/</guid>
      <description>Creativity is like a muscle, being creative requires exercise. Though it can be hard getting started with exercising creativity, just like getting started with physical activities. Once we get started and see the fruits of our efforts, procrastination wouldn&amp;rsquo;t threaten our progress.
What am I going to write about? Finding ideas can be the hardest part of getting started with writing. As I sat down to write at my first attempt, I had a feeling that my mind was like a jar full of sandy water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of a note-taking app / Part 2 - On hobby projects</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-06-15-making-of-a-note-taking-app-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 18:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-06-15-making-of-a-note-taking-app-part2/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I reflected on the reasons to build this application. I gained many experiences along the journey. There are lots of content on the internet about the usage of tools and they get outdated quickly. Therefore I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts and opinions about building a side project, rather than teaching how to use the tools I used.
Before starting to code, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple of code snippets from unfinished side projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying motivated for writing</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 18:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated/</guid>
      <description>There are many reasons to write, as I discussed in my previous post. Writing is an essential form of communication, just like speaking. It builds bridges between us, but it&amp;rsquo;s not flawless. We might not be able to transmit every single detail in our minds. Writers are limited with their abilities to use the language while writing what&amp;rsquo;s on their minds. Readers are restricted with their understanding of language and the meanings they give to the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying motivated for writing</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated-for-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated-for-writing/</guid>
      <description>There are many reasons to write, as I discussed in my previous post. Writing is an essential form of communication, just like speaking. It builds bridges between us, but it&amp;rsquo;s not flawless. We might not be able to transmit every single detail in our minds. Writers are limited with their abilities to use the language while writing what&amp;rsquo;s on their minds. Readers are restricted with their understanding of language and the meanings they give to the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is worth to write</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-27-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 14:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-27-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>Humans leave their mark on the world. It can be something physical, like buildings. Or it can be something abstract which we can only grasp with our minds - such as ideas. Or both; it can conduct ideas or thoughts, give inspiration to others through a physical thing. I would like to reflect on writing, which is a nice way to leave a mark on the world.
In the physical world, we apply pressure on surfaces with a tool such as a pen, to form some signs or letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of a note-taking app / Part 1 - Why I started building it</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-26-making-of-a-note-taking-app-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 08:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-26-making-of-a-note-taking-app-1/</guid>
      <description>The pandemic gave me a lot of boredom. And boredom has different effects on different people: some try new things, some rediscover usual hobbies or activities. Living under lockdown conditions made me try new things especially at home: I built shelves and decoration articles from wood and scratched wallpapers to make the living room look like a cafe for example. I spent much time with plants as well. I planted a couple of avocado seeds like many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Löve2D based game as a web app</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2019-02-10-deploying-love2d-based-game-to-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2019-02-10-deploying-love2d-based-game-to-the-web/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote a blog post about anything and did something in the field of game development. Well, this time it started with some game development and it leaded to this blog post.
Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a Global Game Jam event in Hamburg with @Sarge and it was quite fun. (I will write another blog post about Global Game Jams later) It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first attendance in the Global Game Jam actually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A starter graphql project - Part 2 (UI with VueJs)</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-05-23-a-starter-graphql-project-part-2-ui-with-vuejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 20:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-05-23-a-starter-graphql-project-part-2-ui-with-vuejs/</guid>
      <description>In March, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed and shared a starter graphql project, which is initially intended to be a bootstrapper for Nodejs based Graphql APIs.
This time, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a vue-js frontend to the stack. It uses apollo-clientfor communicating with the backend.
UI is optimized for mobile devices.
Frontend application is capable to
 create an user login logout list existing records search records create a record edit a record delete a record  Screenshots Live demo is available: https://vue-nodejs-graphql-starter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an analog lens with a digital SLR camera</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-03-12-using-an-analog-lens-with-a-digital-slr-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 22:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-03-12-using-an-analog-lens-with-a-digital-slr-camera/</guid>
      <description>There are many decent lenses for analog cameras on the market, produced decades ago and still usable today. Some of them could even outperform the ones produced for digital SLR cameras. It&amp;rsquo;s always possible to find a good one with a good price in a flee market nearby. You can find excellent lenses that worth hundreds of Euros for a price under 50 Euros. Especially the ones made for shooting macro photographs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A starter project for developing a graphql api with nodejs</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-03-08-a-starter-project-for-developing-a-graphql-api-with-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-03-08-a-starter-project-for-developing-a-graphql-api-with-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>A starter API project with nodejs + express + mongodb + graphql (apollo) stack, secured by jsonwebtoken. This repository will be a starting point for my upcoming nodejs based graphql projects. Can be a starting point for anyone who is interested in learning graphql too!
Github: https://github.com/alperklc/express-mongo-graphql-starter
Using a mongo database on default port and creating two collections: User and Record. Collections have a 1-n relation.
Api is running on port number 3333, serving two endpoints:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bypass internet filtering by building your own tiny proxy server</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-02-23-bypass-internet-filtering-by-building-your-own-tiny-proxy-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2018-02-23-bypass-internet-filtering-by-building-your-own-tiny-proxy-server/</guid>
      <description>The project is called your-own-personal-proxy. I started coding this 10 days ago. There are actually solutions for users living in the countries where internet is censored. Either free or paid, there are always risks when it comes to privacy, while surfing behind a tunnelling website or any kind of VPN service. Rolling your own solution might be the safest, unless cloud provider is not sharing the data of users.
The repository includes a nodejs application which is designed for tunneling the traffic between server and the client.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
