<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>writing on Alper Kilci&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in writing on Alper Kilci&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:48:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things to write about</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-07-02-things-to-write-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-07-02-things-to-write-about/</guid>
      <description>Creativity is like a muscle, being creative requires exercise. Though it can be hard getting started with exercising creativity, just like getting started with physical activities. Once we get started and see the fruits of our efforts, procrastination wouldn&amp;rsquo;t threaten our progress.
What am I going to write about? Finding ideas can be the hardest part of getting started with writing. As I sat down to write at my first attempt, I had a feeling that my mind was like a jar full of sandy water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of a note-taking app / Part 2 - On hobby projects</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-06-15-making-of-a-note-taking-app-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 18:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-06-15-making-of-a-note-taking-app-part2/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I reflected on the reasons to build this application. I gained many experiences along the journey. There are lots of content on the internet about the usage of tools and they get outdated quickly. Therefore I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts and opinions about building a side project, rather than teaching how to use the tools I used.
Before starting to code, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple of code snippets from unfinished side projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying motivated for writing</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 18:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated/</guid>
      <description>There are many reasons to write, as I discussed in my previous post. Writing is an essential form of communication, just like speaking. It builds bridges between us, but it&amp;rsquo;s not flawless. We might not be able to transmit every single detail in our minds. Writers are limited with their abilities to use the language while writing what&amp;rsquo;s on their minds. Readers are restricted with their understanding of language and the meanings they give to the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying motivated for writing</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated-for-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-05-10-staying-motivated-for-writing/</guid>
      <description>There are many reasons to write, as I discussed in my previous post. Writing is an essential form of communication, just like speaking. It builds bridges between us, but it&amp;rsquo;s not flawless. We might not be able to transmit every single detail in our minds. Writers are limited with their abilities to use the language while writing what&amp;rsquo;s on their minds. Readers are restricted with their understanding of language and the meanings they give to the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is worth to write</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-27-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 14:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-27-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>Humans leave their mark on the world. It can be something physical, like buildings. Or it can be something abstract which we can only grasp with our minds - such as ideas. Or both; it can conduct ideas or thoughts, give inspiration to others through a physical thing. I would like to reflect on writing, which is a nice way to leave a mark on the world.
In the physical world, we apply pressure on surfaces with a tool such as a pen, to form some signs or letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of a note-taking app / Part 1 - Why I started building it</title>
      <link>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-26-making-of-a-note-taking-app-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 08:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.alperkilci.com/blog/post/2021-04-26-making-of-a-note-taking-app-1/</guid>
      <description>The pandemic gave me a lot of boredom. And boredom has different effects on different people: some try new things, some rediscover usual hobbies or activities. Living under lockdown conditions made me try new things especially at home: I built shelves and decoration articles from wood and scratched wallpapers to make the living room look like a cafe for example. I spent much time with plants as well. I planted a couple of avocado seeds like many people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
